removeandreplace.com 2019-04-27

# Privacy Policy | RemoveandReplace.com

## **Privacy matters but it can get confusing. This privacy page explains our approach to privacy on our website and how it affects you.**

This is the Privacy Policy for **RemoveAndReplace.com** , accessible from **<https://removeandreplace.com/privacy-policy/>**

### Short Privacy Policy Version

  * Anonymous statistics are collected about your visit to our website, including which of our pages you viewed.
  * If you make a comment on our site we take great care to keep your information safe and we’ll never share it with others without your express permission.
  * 3rd parties use cookies to analyze traffic, stats, and other items to help us understand our internet traffic and statistics.
  * Our posts may contain references to products from one or more of our advertisers. We may receive compensation when you click on links to those products.

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

### Information Collection And Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

### Types of Data Collected

### Personal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

 _Email address_  
_First name and last name_  
_Cookies and Usage Data_  
_Contact Forms_

Personal data is captured when someone submits a contact form. We keep contact form submissions on our site for customer service purposes. We do not use the information submitted through them for marketing purposes.

We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

### Embedded Content

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Usage Data

We may also collect information how the Service is accessed and used (“Usage Data”). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

### Tracking & Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

### Examples of Cookies we use:

Session Cookies. We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.  
Preference Cookies. We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.  
Security Cookies. We use Security Cookies for security purposes.

### Use of Data

### What Are Cookies

As is common practice with almost all professional websites this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or ‘break’ certain elements of the sites functionality.

For more general information on cookies see the [Wikipedia article on HTTP Cookies](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie).

### How We Use Cookies

We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case they are used to provide a service that you use.

### Disabling Cookies

You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser _(see your browser Help for how to do this)_. Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of the this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies.

### The Cookies We Set

  * Account related cookies – If you create an account with us then we will use cookies for the management of the signup process and general administration. These cookies will usually be deleted when you log out however in some cases they may remain afterwards to remember your site preferences when logged out.
  * Login related cookies – We use cookies when you are logged in so that we can remember this fact. This prevents you from having to log in every single time you visit a new page. These cookies are typically removed or cleared when you log out to ensure that you can only access restricted features and areas when logged in.
  * Email newsletters related cookies – This site offers newsletter or email subscription services and cookies may be used to remember if you are already registered and whether to show certain notifications which might only be valid to subscribed/unsubscribed users.
  * Surveys related cookies – From time to time we offer user surveys and questionnaires to provide you with interesting insights, helpful tools, or to understand our user base more accurately. These surveys may use cookies to remember who has already taken part in a survey or to provide you with accurate results after you change pages.
  * Forms related cookies – When you submit data to through a form such as those found on contact pages or comment forms cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.
  * Site preferences cookies – In order to provide you with a great experience on this site we provide the functionality to set your preferences for how this site runs when you use it. In order to remember your preferences we need to set cookies so that this information can be called whenever you interact with a page is affected by your preferences.

### Third Party Cookies

In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.

  * This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.  _For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official[Google Analytics page](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage)._
  * Third party analytics are used to track and measure usage of this site so that we can continue to produce engaging content. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site or pages you visit which helps us to understand how we can improve the site for you.
  * From time to time we test new features and make subtle changes to the way that the site is delivered. When we are still testing new features these cookies may be used to ensure that you receive a consistent experience whilst on the site whilst ensuring we understand which optimisations our users appreciate the most.
  * This site uses Amazon direct affiliate links and product imbeds to show our readers suggestions for certain appliance parts and components. These embedded Amazon products show on most pages. There are also links within pages that direct the user to parts or products that will assist in repair or completion.  _For more information on Amazon cookies, see the official_ _ _[ _Amazon Policies for GDPR_](https://advertising.amazon.com/ad-specs/en/policy/gdpr) _._
  * As we sell products it’s important for us to understand statistics about how many of the visitors to our site actually make a purchase and as such this is the kind of data that these cookies will track. This is important to you as it means that we can accurately make business predictions that allow us to monitor our advertising and product costs to ensure the best possible price.
  * The Google AdSense service we use to serve advertising uses a DoubleClick cookie to serve more relevant ads across the web and limit the number of times that a given ad is shown to you.  _For more information on Google AdSense see the official[Google AdSense privacy FAQ](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads)._
  * We use adverts to offset the costs of running this site and provide funding for further development. The behavioural advertising cookies used by this site are designed to ensure that we provide you with the most relevant adverts where possible by anonymously tracking your interests and presenting similar things that may be of interest.
  * Several partners advertise on our behalf and affiliate tracking cookies simply allow us to see if our customers have come to the site through one of our partner sites so that we can credit them appropriately and where applicable allow our affiliate partners to provide any bonus that they may provide you for making a purchase.
  * We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways. For these to work the following social media sites including; Facebook, WhatsApp, Reddit, Twitter, and Pinterest, will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.

 **RemoveAndReplace.com** uses the collected data for various purposes:

To provide and maintain the Service  
To notify you about changes to our Service  
To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so  
To provide customer care and support  
To provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the Service  
To monitor the usage of the Service  
To detect, prevent and address technical issues

### Transfer Of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

 **RemoveAndReplace.com** will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

### Rights Of Data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Disclosure Of Data

### Legal Requirements

 **RemoveAndReplace.com** may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

To comply with a legal obligation  
To protect and defend the rights or property of RemoveandReplace  
To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service  
To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public  
To protect against legal liability

### Security Of Data

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

### Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers such as Google Analytics to monitor and analyze the use of our Service. You can learn more about Google Analytics or opt out if you prefer.

### Ad Network

For full details about our ad network and it’s privacy policies – [Policies Google FAQ](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

### Links To Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

### Children’s Privacy

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”).

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

### Activity Log

 **Data Used:** To deliver this functionality and record activities around site management, the following information is captured: user email address, user role, user login, user display name, WordPress.com and local user IDs, the activity to be recorded, the WordPress.com-connected site ID of the site on which the activity takes place, the site’s Jetpack version, and the timestamp of the activity. Some activities may also include the actor’s IP address (login attempts, for example) and user agent.

 **Activity Tracked:** Login attempts/actions, post and page update and publish actions, comment/pingback submission and management actions, plugin and theme management actions, widget updates, user management actions, and the modification of other various site settings and options. Retention duration of activity data depends on the site’s plan and activity type. [See the complete list of currently-recorded activities (along with retention information)](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/activity-log/#data-retention).

 **Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** Successful and failed login attempts, which will include the actor’s IP address and user agent.

* * *

### Contact Form

 **Data Used:** If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, the contact form submission data — IP address, user agent, name, email address, website, and message — is submitted to the [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) service (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) for the sole purpose of spam checking. The actual submission data is stored in the database of the site on which it was submitted and is emailed directly to the owner of the form (i.e. the site author who published the page on which the contact form resides). This email will include the submitter’s IP address, timestamp, name, email address, website, and message.

 **Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** Post and post meta data associated with a user’s contact form submission. If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, the IP address and user agent originally submitted with the comment are synced, as well, as they are stored in post meta.

* * *

### Google Analytics

 **Data Used:** Please refer to the appropriate [Google Analytics documentation](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsTrackingOverview#howAnalyticsGetsData) for the specific type of data it collects. For sites running [WooCommerce](https://woocommerce.com/) (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) and this feature simultaneously and having all purchase tracking explicitly enabled, purchase events will send Google Analytics the following information: order number, product id and name, product category, total cost, and quantity of items purchased. Google Analytics does offer [IP anonymization](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en), which can be enabled by the site owner.

 **Activity Tracked:** This feature sends page view events (and potentially [video play events](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#video-hosting)) over to Google Analytics for consumption. For sites running WooCommerce-powered stores, some additional events are also sent to Google Analytics: shopping cart additions and removals, product listing views and clicks, product detail views, and purchases. Tracking for each specific WooCommerce event needs to be enabled by the site owner.

* * *

### Gravatar Hovercards

 **Data Used:** This feature will send a hash of the user’s email address (if logged in to the site or WordPress.com — or if they submitted a comment on the site using their email address that is attached to an active Gravatar profile) to the [Gravatar](https://gravatar.com/) service (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) in order to retrieve their profile image.

* * *

### Jetpack Comments

 **Data Used:** Commenter’s name, email address, and site URL (if provided via the comment form), timestamp, and IP address. Additionally, a jetpack.wordpress.com IFrame receives the following data: WordPress.com blog ID attached to the site, ID of the post on which the comment is being submitted, commenter’s local user ID (if available), commenter’s local username (if available), commenter’s site URL (if available), MD5 hash of the commenter’s email address (if available), and the comment content. If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) is enabled on the site, the following information is sent to the service for the sole purpose of spam checking: commenter’s name, email address, site URL, IP address, and user agent.

 **Activity Tracked:** The comment author’s name, email address, and site URL (if provided during the comment submission) are stored in cookies. [Learn more about these cookies](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#comments).

 **Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** All data and metadata (see above) associated with comments. This includes the status of the comment and, if [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, whether or not it was classified as spam by Akismet.

* * *

### Mobile Theme

 **Data Used:** A visitor’s preference on viewing the mobile version of a site.

 **Activity Tracked:** A cookie (`akm_mobile`) is stored for 3.5 days to remember whether or not a visitor of the site wishes to view its mobile version. [Learn more about this cookie](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#mobile-theme).

* * *

### Notifications

 **Data Used:** IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID and URL, Jetpack version, user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code. Some visitor-related information or activity may be sent to the site owner via this feature. This may include: email address, WordPress.com username, site URL, email address, comment content, follow actions, etc.

 **Activity Tracked:** Sending notifications (i.e. when we send a notification to a particular user), opening notifications (i.e. when a user opens a notification that they receive), performing an action from within the notification panel (e.g. liking a comment or marking a comment as spam), and clicking on any link from within the notification panel/interface.

* * *

### Protect

 **Data Used:** In order to check login activity and potentially block fraudulent attempts, the following information is used: attempting user’s IP address, attempting user’s email address/username (i.e. according to the value they were attempting to use during the login process), and all IP-related HTTP headers attached to the attempting user.

 **Activity Tracked:** Failed login attempts (these include IP address and user agent). We also set a cookie (`jpp_math_pass`) for 1 day to remember if/when a user has successfully completed a math captcha to prove that they’re a real human. [Learn more about this cookie.](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#protect)

 **Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** Failed login attempts, which contain the user’s IP address, attempted username or email address, and user agent information.

* * *

### Search

 **Data Used:** Any of the visitor-chosen search filters and query data in order to process a search request on the WordPress.com servers.

* * *

### Sharing

 **Data Used:** When sharing content via email (this option is only available if [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is active on the site), the following information is used: sharing party’s name and email address (if the user is logged in, this information will be pulled directly from their account), IP address (for spam checking), user agent (for spam checking), and email body/content. This content will be sent to [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) so that a spam check can be performed. Additionally, if [reCAPTCHA](http://www.google.com/recaptcha) (by Google) is enabled by the site owner, the sharing party’s IP address will be shared with that service. You can find Google’s privacy policy [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

* * *

### Subscriptions

 **Data Used:** To initiate and process subscriptions, the following information is used: subscriber’s email address and the ID of the post or comment (depending on the specific subscription being processed). In the event of a new subscription being initiated, we also collect some basic server data, including all of the subscribing user’s HTTP request headers, the IP address from which the subscribing user is viewing the page, and the URI which was given in order to access the page (`REQUEST_URI` and `DOCUMENT_URI`). This server data used for the exclusive purpose of monitoring and preventing abuse and spam.

 **Activity Tracked:** [Functionality cookies](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#subscriptions) are set for a duration of **347 days** to remember a visitor’s blog and post subscription choices if, in fact, they have an active subscription.

* * *

### WordPress.com Secure Sign On

 **Data Used:** User ID (local site and WordPress.com), role (e.g. administrator), email address, username and display name. Additionally, for activity tracking (see below): IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID and URL, Jetpack version, user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

 **Activity Tracked:** The following usage events are recorded: starting the login process, completing the login process, failing the login process, successfully being redirected after login, and failing to be redirected after login. Several functionality cookies are also set, and these are detailed explicitly in our [Cookie documentation](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#sso).

 **Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** The user ID and role of any user who successfully signed in via this feature.

* * *

### WordPress.com Stats

 **Data Used:** IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code. _Important:_ The site owner does **not** have access to any of this information via this feature. For example, a site owner can see that a specific post has 285 views, but he/she cannot see which specific users/accounts viewed that post. Stats logs — containing visitor IP addresses and WordPress.com usernames (if available) — are retained by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/) for 28 days and are used for the sole purpose of powering this feature.

 **Activity Tracked:** Post and page views, [video plays](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#video-hosting) (if videos are hosted by WordPress.com), outbound link clicks, referring URLs and search engine terms, and country. When this module is enabled, Jetpack also tracks performance on each page load that includes the Javascript file used for tracking stats. This is exclusively for aggregate performance tracking across Jetpack sites in order to make sure that our plugin and code is not causing performance issues. This includes the tracking of page load times and resource loading duration (image files, Javascript files, CSS files, etc.). The site owner has the ability to force this feature [to honor DNT settings of visitors](https://jetpack.com/support/wordpress-com-stats/#honoring-dnt). By default, DNT is currently not honored.

* * *

### WordPress.com Toolbar

 **Data Used:** Gravatar image URL of the logged-in user in order to display it in the toolbar and the WordPress.com user ID of the logged-in user. Additionally, for activity tracking (detailed below): IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID and URL, Jetpack version, user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

 **Activity Tracked:** Click actions within the toolbar.

 **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will let you know with a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the “effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

 **More Information**

Hopefully that has clarified things for you and as was previously mentioned if there is something that you aren’t sure whether you need or not it’s usually safer to leave cookies enabled in case it does interact with one of the features you use on our site.

 **Contact Us**

Please feel free to contact us with any questions you have over concern of privacy.

  * Contact us by visiting this page on our website: [https://removeandreplace/contact/](https://removeandreplace.com/contact/)

**More "Do It Yourself" DIY Tips, Tricks, Ideas, Repair:**
